Long live The Stooges!
Gimme Danger is a documentary, music film directed by Jim Jarmusch.
No other band in rock'n'roll history has rivaled The Stooges' combination of heavy primal throb, spiked psychedelia, blues-a-billy grind, complete with succinct
angst-ridden lyrics, and a snarling, preening leopard of a frontman who somehow embodies Nijinsky, Bruce Lee, Harpo Marx, and Arthur Rimbaud all rolled into one.
There is no precedent for The Stooges, while those
inspired by them are now legion.
The film will present the context of their emergence musically, culturally, politically, historically, and relate their adventures and misadventures
while charting their inspirations and the reasons behind their initial commercial challenges, as well as their long-lasting legacy.
Self, played by Iggy Pop.
Self, played by Scott Asheton.
Self, played by James Williamson.
Self, played by Dave Alexander.
Self, played by Steve Mackay.
Self, played by Mike Watt.
Gimme Danger  is a 2016 American documentary film directed
by Jim Jarmusch about the band the Stooges.
It was shown in the Midnight Screenings section
at the 2016 Cannes Film Festival.
The film was released by Amazon Studios and
Magnolia Pictures on October 28, 2016.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll, punk
rock, rock band, detroit, michigan.